A Guide to the Governor Terry McAuliffe, Policy Office, Records, 2002; 2006-2008; 2010-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Library of Virginia
- II. Subject Files, 2004; 2006-2008; 2010-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 8.68 cubic feet (14 boxes). (Box 11-24)
  - Subseries II.D. Jay Swanson, Deputy Policy Director, 2008; 2014-2015., Extent: 1.28 cubic feet (3 boxes) (Box 19-22)
    - Uber, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Department of Transportation (VDOT), 2014. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Energy Plan, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Weekly Check-Ins, undated. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II.E. Suzanne Gore, Policy Advisor, 2016-2017., Extent: 3 folders (Box 23)
    This subseries is housed in three (3) folders. The records were in no discernible order; the processing archivist created folder titles for all records. During the McAuliffe administration, Suzanne Gore served as Deputy Secretary of Health and Human Resources, Deputy Director of the Virginia Medicaid Program and a senior advisory on healthcare. Notable subjects in this subseries include: healthcare and Medicaid expansion. See also Series I.B.5 - Legislative Files (Policy Analysts), Suzanne Gore.
    - Records, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Records, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Records, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Subseries IV.F. Massey Whorley, Senior Policy Advisor, 2016-2017., Extent: 15 folders (Box 23)
    This subseries is housed in fifteen (15) folders. The original order has been maintained. Massey Whorley served as a senior policy advisor from September 2016 to January 2018. He policy assignment was health and human resources with a focus on healthcare and the Affordable Care Act. See also Series I.B.4 - Legislative Files (Policy Analysts), Massey Whorley.
    - Affordable Care Act (ACA) Open Enrollment, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Medicaid Reform, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Meetings of Legislative Committees, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Center for Health Innovation (VCHI), 2017. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Opioids, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Market-Based Sourcing, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Jails/Mental Health/Opioids, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Consumer Directed Care, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Meetings with Lobbyists, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Children's Services Act (CSA), 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - System Transformation, Excellence and Performance in Virginia (STEP-VA)/Mental Health Funding, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Upper Payment Limits (UPL), 2016. (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Health Care Coalitions, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Affordable Care Act (ACA) Repeal, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Subseries II.G. Matt West, Policy Assistant, 2017., Extent: 4 folders (Box 23)
    This subseries is housed in four (4) folders. The original order has been maintained. In August 2017, Matt West was appointed tot he position of policy assistant. West previously served as 2017 Governor's Fellow.
    - Commonwealth Commission on Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion (DEI), 2017. (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Campaign Promises, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Agency Legislation, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Subseries II.H. Margaret Chambers, Special Assistant for Policy, 2015-2016., Extent: 10 folders (Box 23)
    This subseries is housed in ten (10) folders. Arranged loosely by subject, the original has been maintained. Margaret Chambers served as special assistant for policy from October 2016 to May 2017. Chambers previously served as special assistant to the Secretary of Education and support staff to the SOL Innovation and School Readiness Committees from October 2016 to September 2016. Chambers was also a 2014 Governor's Fellow. Her policy assignment was education. From May 2017 to January 2018, she served as special policy advisor to First Lady Dorothy McAuliffe. See also Series I.B.7 - Legislative Files (Policy Analysts), Margaret Chambers.
    - Meeting Notes and Handouts, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Meeting with Just Children, 1 December 2016. (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Project Moonshot, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Comments on Every Student Succeeds Act (ESSA), 2016. (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Governor's Schools Report, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Children's Cabinet, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - P-20 Council, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Project Discovery Meeting, 21 November 2016. (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Meetings, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Cyber Security, Higher Education in Virginia, 2015. (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Subseries II.I. Erik Johnston, Deputy Policy Director, 2016-2017., Extent: 1 folder (Box 23)
    This subseries is housed in one (1) folder. The original order has been maintained. Erik Johnston served as deputy policy director from November 2015 to April 2017. His policy assignments were ABC, natural resources and transportation.
    - Rockbridge County Towers, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Don Horsley/Delegate Barry Knight, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - ABC-Everclear, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - VDOT-Richmond-GAB Bank Street, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Notepad, undated. (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Lexington-VDOT Property, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Subseries II.J. Connor Andrews, Policy Assistant, 2016-2018., Extent: 12 folders (Box 23)
    This subseries is housed in twelve (12) folders. The processing archivist created folder titles for this subseries. Connor Andrews was appointed policy assistant in May 2017, a position he held until the end of the McAuliffe administration. Andrews interned in the Office of the Secretary of Education and previously served as 2016 Governor's Fellow. His policy assignments were commerce and trade and education. See also Series I.B.3 - Legislative Files (Policy Analysts), Connor Andrews.
    - Education, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Education, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Notes (handwritten), 2017. (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Updates to the Governor's Campaign Promises, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - JLARC, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Economic Development, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence, 2017-2018. (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Gold Sheets, 2016-2017. (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Pretrial Services in Virginia, 2016. (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - 21st Century Workforce, undated. (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Condition of College and Career Readiness, 2017. (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Opioid and Heroin Stakeholders Meeting, 21 June 2017. (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Subseries II.K. Miscellaneous, 2014-2017., Extent: 1.0 cubic foot (1 box) (Box 24)
    This subseries is housed in one (1) box. The Miscellaneous subseries contains records where the ownership was unclear. Arranged alphabetically by the processing archivist, notable subjects include the 2016 Governor's Fellows research project and briefing binders of annual meeting of Virginia's Congressional Delegation.
    - 2016 Governor's Fellows
      - Cyber Security and Unmanned Systems Roundtable, 22 July 2016. (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Education Matrix, 2016. (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - General Assembly Information, 2016. (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - McAuliffe Administration Priorities, 2016. (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Student Debt Research (1 of 2), 2016. (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Student Debt Research (2 of 2), 2016. (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Retirement System (VRS), 2016. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Briefing Binder, Meeting with the Virginia Congressional Delegate (Governor's Copy), 14 April 2015. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Briefing Binder, Meeting with the Virginia Congressional Delegate (Secretary of Finance's Copy), 22 March 2017. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Briefing Binder, Meeting with the Virginia Congressional Delegate (Congressman Wittman's Copy), 22 March 2017. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2016-2017. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Education-Virginia 529 Briefing for Governor Terry McAuliffe, July 2014. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - VCU Commonwealth Education Poll, 2015-2016. (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Virginia. Dept. of Elections, Photo ID Implementation and Public Outreach, 5 September 2014. (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Executive Agreements, undated. (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Healthy Food, 2015. (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Job's for America's Graduates (JAG), Board of Director's Meeting, 10 November 2016. (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Legislation Review, 2014; 2017. (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - NASA, SLS and Orion Supplies Conference, 23-24 February 2016. (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Publications, 2014; 2017. (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Secretary of Commerce and Trade, 2015 Legislative Proposals, 2014. (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Secretary of Public Safety and Homeland Security, 2014; undated. (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Secretary of Transportation, 2016-2017. (Box 24, Folder 23)